I PRABU

Database Support Engineer

iprabu1409@gmail.com +91 9944030828 Nagercoil,India www.linkedin.com/in/iprabu14

www.github.com/iPrabu14 iprabu14.github.io/Portfolio

OBJECTIVE

To provide the company with the maximum knowledge that I have gained till now and be able to learn while working on a professional platform along with a motto of acquiring a lot of new skills that the company can nurture me with. The primary aim is to learn about the inexperienced aspects and functioning of an IT organisation.

EXPERIENCE

Database Support Engineer

GK Microsystems

Apr 2022 - 2024* Nagercoil

- •I have experience working on database management and contributing to applications. My tasks involved ensuring efficient data organization, retrieval, and management.
- Reported Development using SQL queries and Crystal Reports and Business Objects.
- •Installed, configured, and maintained database server software and related products.

Junior System Administrator

Perfect Systems

Aug 2021 - Mar 2022 Nagercoil

- Configured and maintained adiverse range of systems including servers, databases, and networking equipment, utilizing technologies such as Linux, Windows Server, and VMware.
- Provided support to local end users and remote users Hardware software and ApplicationProblems.

INTERNSHIPS

Hardware and Networking - Kaassiv InfoTech, Chennai.

Web App Development - Trinity Soft. Technologies, Tvm.

PROJECTS

Multilevel Histogram Specification for Image Enhancement.

Multilevel histogram specification is a technique used in image enhancement to manipulate the histogram of an image to match a specified histogram.

Histogram is a graphical representation that shows the distribution of pixel intensities values in an image. It displays the frequency of occurrence of each intensity level.

Memory Challenge Game.

Developed a dynamic and challenging "Memory Challenge Game" using HTML,CSS, and JavaScript. The game interface presents four distinct colors, requiring players to memorize and replicate the sequence of colors clicked in each round.

The game mechanics involve remembering and replicating the sequence accurately any deviation results in the termination of the game.

CERTIFIED COURSES

Python

GUVI Geek Networks

Aug 2023

The Complete Web Development Bootcamp

Udemy

Nov 2022

Foundation in Hardware and Networking

Networkz Systems

Aug 2020 -Oct 2020 Nagercoil
Diploma in Advanced Network
Administration

Networkz Systems

Aug 2020 -Oct 2020 Nagercoil

SKILL SETS

- Microsoft SQLSeverPostgreSQL
- Database Administration Performance Tuning
- •SQL Server Management Studio
- •Python •MsAccess •MsExcel
- Web Development

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

Anna University 2016- 2020

Ponjesly College of

Engineering Nagercoil

Higher Secondary Certificate

State Board,TN 2015–2016

Government Higher

Secondary School Kattathurai

Secondary School Leaving Certificate

State Board,TN 2014-2015

Government Higher

Secondary School Kattathurai